A lot of students are dressing up
for this year's Tsuwabuki Fest.
It's not unlike Halloween.
Hey, get out of my way!
Oh, I've seen that exact line...
in light novels before.
I've seen this in light novels, too.
I'm really sorry! Are you sure you're okay?
Does anything hurt? Any bumps anywhere?
Uh, well...
Thanks for your concern.
I should be the one thanking you.
You're even carrying half my stuff for me.
Hey, hey!
Let's walk to the classroom together.
I've been wanting to talk to you, anyway.
Sosuke and Anna are always talking about you,
so it almost feels like I know you.
Um, I do talk to Hakamada sometimes,
but it's not like we're really friends.
Oh, really?
Then why don't you become
friends with both of us?
Okay?
Oh, no! She's so dazzling,
she's gonna kill me!
It's almost like Himemiya-san
has light affinity.
She definitely has a certain
something that Yanami doesn't.
It's like TV, where you think, "Wow, 4K
looks awesome!" And then 8K comes out...
Oh, it's 4K.
For-kay?
No, never mind.
Tsuwabuki Fest Is In
Days
Y-You're late. Where were you?
I had a meeting about my class event.
Didn't you have one?
N-No.
Nobody in class told me anything.
O-Oh. I guess not, then.
Try these out.
First, the sugar-coated peanuts
Natsume Soseki liked so much.
I gave it a modern update with
cocoa powder, so give it a taste.
Oh, yum! D-Did you make this, Nukumizu?
No, my little sister did.
Same with the others.
Th-Then what did you do?
I washed dishes and gave her
shoulder massages and stuff.
Oh, I also did the packaging.
Next up is Dazai's. We made a cherry
pound cake for his story "Cherries."
I think this one tastes the best.
It's m-marbled? It's so pretty.
We used canned dark cherries and syrup
to add color. Well, my sister did.
The next two are from the picture books
Swimmy and Guri and Gura.
J-Just like in the b-books!
Y-Your little sister is amazing.
But see these bags? I picked them.
I could use some praise, too, you know.
N-Nukumizu, w-way to go.
Yes! I am the first-born son!
See what I can do when I put my mind to it?
Tsuwabuki Fest Is In
Days
So I guess we're good for the snacks.
W-We also need recipes
and instructions with pictures.
Okay, got it. I'll put those together.
What are all those books?
I-I got them from the public library.
I have to return them today.
How did you get so many of them here?
B-Bit by bit.
Th-The copy machine
here at school is cheaper.
You just returned a bunch
and now you're borrowing more?
I s-still need some to write the exhibit
displays. A-And some are for the rugrats.
The Very
Hungry
Caterpillar
If I don't read them stories before bed,
th-they don't fall asleep.
How are the articles for the displays going?
I-It'll take a little longer.
There are four of them, right?
Let me write one of them.
Y-You haven't finished your newsletter
manuscript, bud. W-Write that!
Okay, I'll write that.
What's wrong?
G-Get your head down.
Um, maybe they were using
one of the third-floor study rooms.
You know, to study for exams.
Machinaka Plaza
Hitohito
N-Nukumizu, y-you're worried about me, right?
A little. I didn't expect them
to show up, so yeah.
I-I don't care. I-I know they're dating.
Holding hands and stuff is normal.
E-Even at school, they're a-always together.
But it's kind of different
when we're not at school.
Outside, it's like they're
in an unfamiliar world.
Like they've found their own
special place to be together.
Hey, there's one more place
I wanna check out. That okay?
Sure.
D-Don't get me wrong. I-I didn't hide
because they were together.
I-It's because in f-first term,
I would've been with them.
I-I'm sad that I can't join them anymore.
Wh-When I joined the club in April,
th-they were both really nice to me.
In c-class, I didn't have any friends.
They spent a bunch of time with me.
Th-That was the first time
I'd ever thought school was fun.
Hitohito
B-But now, it's back to normal.
I'm sure Tsukinoki-senpai would take a
break from studying to see you anytime.
Y-Yeah.
And I don't think the prez
is trying to avoid you at all.
I know. B-But if I hadn't asked him out, maybe
we th-three could've spent more time together.
O-Once Tsuwabuki Fest is over,
they'll both go away,
s-so I have to be able to get by on my own.
If you need anything from me,
just say the word.
I-I can do it by myself.
I have to.
Tsuwabuki Fest Is In
Days
That's it for the pumpkin.
Now I just need the bats.
You look so cute!
You're perfect in that,
Karen-chan! It's super cute!
Himemiya-san's something else.
A demon is one thing,
but she looks like a succubus.
Nuk-kun.
Well? Are you scared?
That's a lot of skin.
Yakishio, you shouldn't show your belly
like that with people around.
But this is how a mummy would look.
Wait. Hold on a second.
Are you naked under those bandages?
Well, yeah. Is that a problem?
I mean, everything's covered—
Amanatsu Crew
And out.
Lemon, you're coming with us.
Hey, what do you boys think you're looking at?
Huh? What's wrong with you all? Hey!
Nukumizu-kun.
Look!
Whaddaya think? Boo!
Um, you're cosplaying as a corpse?
I'm a ghost! Have you ever seen
a corpse looking this healthy?
I've never seen a ghost that healthy, either.
Hey, Yanami.
Practice is starting.
Okay, on my way.
Tsuwabuki Fest Is In
Days
So you wrote a continuation
of the story you wrote at camp?
Yeah, more or less.
And Koto wrote something new.
Yeah, but this one doesn't
have any dirty scenes.
I think she finally caught on about that.
I wish she'd catch on to some other things, too.
Oh, it sounds like Komari-chan's
having trouble with the display articles.
Yeah. I keep telling her I'm willing to help...
Emergency!
It's Komari-chan!
The Complete Works
of Dazai Osamu
She'll be fine. She's just needs sleep.
Nothing to worry about.
Komari-chan...
I know you go through a lot at your age,
trying to push yourselves to your limits.
I had experiences like that, too.
Wanna hear the story?
Uh, no thanks.
Yeah, I think I'm good.
Why did you do this to yourself?
Nukumizu.
Y-Ya dumbbell. That one's the cauliflower.
What the heck is she dreaming about?
Wha—
Wh-Why are you here?!
Konuki-sensei brought you home.
I came along to show her the way.
K-Konuki-sensei, huh?
P-Pajamas?!
Yeah, Konuki-sensei changed
you out of your clothes.
D-Did you look?
I did not look.
Aw, you didn't even look? What a shame.
Sensei, there are small children present.
Are you my sister's boyfriend?
No, I'm not.
Then are you her friend?
Um, we're just in the same club together...
Yes, we're friends.
Hina, see? He's big sis's friend.
Don't be scared.
Just like big sis.
Huh? Yeah, it looks cute.
Huh? What is this adorable creature?
All right, I'll watch over your brother
and sister, so please enjoy yourselves.
Hey, Komari. Why don't you send me
what you've written for the displays so far?
Wh-Why?
You can't keep pushing yourself like this.
B-But...
You should rest and let me do the—
I-I'll finish them!
I'll finish them. J-Just let me do the writing.
When will you be done?
B-By tomorrow morning.
Okay. When you're done,
send the data to everyone in the club.
Th-Thanks.
But in exchange, I want you
to promise me something.
Promise you?
Let us handle everything else for the exhibit.
You stay home tomorrow and get some rest.
If you do, I'll let you finish writing.
B-But we have to set up tomorrow.
Well, maybe you should let me show
what I can do just this once.
How was Komari-chan?
She seemed better after she got some sleep.
Oh, good.
We want her to still have fun
at school even after we're gone.
We wanted the literature club to
become a place where she'd belong.
And we've been trying to watch over her...
You told me before that you want
to help Komari get stronger.
But you know what?
Tsuwabuki Fest Is In
Days
I think she's a little stronger than you think.
Turn off
Snooze
Alarm
Tsuwabuki High School Literature Club
Unread Messages
Komari Chika
Thank you
very much
That early morning tap
water sure hits the spot.
Well, then.
Nuk-kun.
Yakishio?
I thought I told you to leave
the heavy lifting to me.
But why are you here?
We were supposed to set up after homeroom.
Yana-chan told me you were
gonna try to do it all yourself.
Tuna and mayo is the
pinnacle of human wisdom.
Whoever invented this
deserves the Yanami Prize.
And Yanami-san? Why?
Who do you think we are? We're members, too.
And we're worried about Komari-chan.
Yeah, yeah. We can't let
you push yourself too hard.
But I'm not pushing myself. I was just
going to get as much done as I could.
Well, asking your friends for help
is one of the things you could do.
Have you all completely forgotten about us?
Senpai?
I bet there's something
we can help out with, too.
Especially after all you did during vacation.
Lemon-san forwarded me
the reports for the displays.
I looked through them on the way to school
and drafted some ideas for the layout.
You "looked" through them?
Wait, that's like 50,000 characters!
Yes, it was very impressive!
I could sense the author's passion throughout.
It's all wonderfully written.
All right. Ayano-kun, Asagumo-san,
and I will work on the displays.
Nukumizu and Koto can do
the layout and room prep.
Yanami-san and Yakishio-san,
whenever you get a break from class prep,
come give Nukumizu a hand.
C'mon, Nukumizu-kun, get in here.
O-Oh, right.
All right, Tsuwabuki Fest starts tomorrow!
Let's all work hard and do this!
Yeah!
Y-Yeah!
Okay!
Okay, here we go!
Thanks, everyone!
Well? Are you impressed with your
charismatic consultant, Yanami-chan, yet?
Edible
Readings
Sugar-Coated Peanuts
Yup. Perfect.
The main event hasn't started yet.
Nukumizu Kazuhiko
Nu
We've finished setting up
Everything's
perfect
"We've finished setting up.
Everything's perfect."
Hey there.
Wow, things are looking good here.
That's the research report on Dazai.
It draws from the short story "Cherries"
and takes a look at Dazai's friendships and
his views on family. It's pretty interesting.
"Cherries" as in the fruit?
I've never read it, but judging from
the title, I bet it's a really cute story.
Well, pretty much. Basically,
the protagonist runs out on his family
and heads to a bar to see some woman.
That isn't exactly what I imagined.
I sure love the smell of tatami mats.
Come on, sit down.
I'll give you one. Let's eat together.
You're giving me something?
Um, does that mean...
You're giving me something to eat?!
Uh, yeah? Why'd you say that twice?
This really is cool, though.
Yeah. I didn't expect the
exhibit to turn out so fancy.
This whole thing is like
Komari-chan's love letter, you know.
I guess that's one way to see it.
You don't see it that way, Nukumizu-kun?
I think this exhibit shows
Komari's memories, her gratitude,
and her dedication as club president.
It's all of that stuff packed in together.
Okay.
I don't want to see it
as something depressing.
I think I kind of understand
Komari-chan's feelings, though.
Komari-chan really treasures
the literature club and her senpai.
But she was ready to let go of those treasures.
She was prepared for that when she
confessed her feelings that night at camp.
Once she settled down, she said she
had completely given up on him,
but when you like someone that much,
those feelings don't just disappear.
Sometimes, you can't tell someone you
like them, and you don't know what to do,
but you still want to find a way
to let those feelings out.
That's why Komari-chan writes,
and why Lemon-chan runs.
And Komari-chan... What else
could she do? It's because she's a girl.
Because she's a girl?
Yeah. She needs to spit those feelings out
and force herself to move on, even if it's hard,
so that she can be ready to fall in love again.
Has Komari found another boy she likes?
Who knows? But she sure is cute.
Nukumizu-kun, if you keep dragging
your feet, you might get left behind.
And what about you, Yanami-san?
You know. The guy in the Shinsengumi costume.
I think that guy has a thing for you.
Are you a tiny bit jealous? Seriously?
What? No!
Oh, gosh. You'd be so heartbroken
if I got a boyfriend!
Nukumizu-kun, you're kind of a sweetie.
Hey, that one's mine.
What? Um...
What are you—
Shh.
Yanami-san.
Huh? J-Just a second.
Nukumizu-kun? It's still too early
for a school festival romance!
No, it's not that.
Huh?
Konuki-sensei's recording a video of us.
Could you please not say anything weird?
What?
Oops.
Episode 9
Consider Your Teacher a Stain on the Ceiling
or Something, and Please Continue